杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 现在我们可以获得定制数据,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Now that we
are able to get that custom data,
我们可以开始使用它。
we can start using it.
让我们把这些东西放到屏幕上。
So let's get these stuff
up onto the screen.
所以我们首先需要的是反应组分
So the first thing that we're gonna need
is we're gonna need react components
在屏幕上显示这些东西。
to actually show this stuff on the screen.
让我们来看看我们的主题文档。
So let's get into our theme docs.
我们要创造一些新的东西。
And we're gonna create
a couple new things.
所以我们首先需要的是一个模板。
So the first thing we want is a template.
这是一个我喜欢的惯例，但并不是必须的。
And this is a convention that I like,
but that is not required.
每当我在《了不起的盖茨比》中以编程方式创建页面时,
Whenever I create pages
programmatically in Gatsby,
我喜欢把它们称为模板，即盖茨比使用的组件
I like to call them templates
the component that gets used by Gatsby's
在 page create 中，我称之为模板，并将它们保存在单独的目录中。
on page create, I call that a template and
I keep those in a separate directory.
所以我要创建源模板和
So I'm gonna create source templates and
我将这个文档页面命名为 template.js。
I'll call this one docs page template.js.
在它里面，我要进口反应从反应和
And inside of it,
I'm going to import react from react and
我将导入 MDXRenderer，所以这是一个
I will import the MDXRenderer,
so this is the helper that
我之前提到过，这将有助于我们展示 MDX 内容是代码。
I was talking about awhile back that'll
help us show that MDX stuff is code.
所以 MDX 给了我们这个，比如这个函数和其他东西
So MDX gives us this,
like this functions and stuff, and
提取出我们使用的布局组件，它包装了所有相同的 MDX
that pulls out that layout component that
we use and it wraps up all the same MDX
这样，如果我们在 MDX 文件中写 React，它就会被渲染。
stuff, so that if we write React inside
of our MDX files it'll get rendered.
但是我们不想手动解析它。
But we don't wanna have
to manually parse that.
因此，Docs 页面模板要做一件事，那就是加载数据。
So the Docs page template is going
to do one thing, which is load data.
然后我们将构建一个 Docs 页面组件来显示数据。
And then we'll build a Docs page
component that will display data.
这是一个非常慎重的选择，将数据的来源分开,
And that's a very deliberate choice
to separate the sourcing of the data,
从数据的显示，因为它的意思是，如果我想作出改变
from the display of the data, because what
it means is that if I wanna make changes
我不想重写整个查询
to one or the other, I don't necessarily
wanna have to rewrite the full query or
重写整个组件。
rewrite the full component.
当我们进入组件阴影时，就更容易理解为什么会这样了
When we get into component shadowing it's
a little easier to understand why that's
这是一个有用的区别。
a helpful distinction to make.
但是，在一个模板中，我们要做的是在上下文中做出反应
But so, in a template what we'll do is
we wanna have React in the context so
我们将进口反应从反应。
we'll import React from React.
然后我们要从 Gatsby 中导入图 qL。
And then we're going to import graph qL,
from Gatsby.
然后我们要导出一个查询。
And then we're going to export a query.
因此，必须导出查询。
So the query, it has to be exported.
它不一定需要被命名为 query。
It doesn't necessarily
need to be named query.
你可以给它起任何名字，但是盖茨比确实要求它是出口的。
You can name it whatever you want, but
Gatsby does require that it is export it.
我们现在所做的就是所谓的页面查询。
And what we're doing here is
what's called a page query.
而且这些只对那些
And these only work on files that will be
作为盖茨比页面创作过程的一部分。
parsed as part of the the page
creation process by Gatsby.
所以在创建页面或者
So in the on Create Page or
创建页面 API 是唯一的时间，这样做的工作。
the create pages API is
the only time that this works.
这就是为什么我喜欢将它们保存在模板下的单独文件夹中，以便
And that's why I like to keep these in
a separate folder under templates so that
更明显的是，它们的处理方式与普通成分不同。
it's more clear that these get handled
differently than the average component.
所以我要写的查询是通过 ID 加载一个页面。
So the query that I wanna write is
going to load a page by its ID.
所以我想要展示的是，我们得到一个身份证，然后
So what I wanna do to show how
that works is, we get an ID, and
我们把问题写在这里吧。
let's just write our query here.
所以，我喜欢在《了不起的盖茨比》中使用 GraphQL 资源管理器,
So, one of the ways that I love to develop
in Gatsby is to use the GraphQL explorer,
然后复制粘贴它，这样我就可以在保存之前验证我的查询是否正常工作
and just copy paste it in so I can verify
that my queries work before I save it and
创业盖茨比。
start up Gatsby.
所以我要做的第一件事就是设置一个查询变量。
So the first thing I'm going to
do is set up a query variable.
我要调用这个页面 ID。
And I'm gonna call this page ID.
页面 ID 将是一个字符串,
And the page ID is going to be a string,
我们会在主页上给出这个 ID。
and we're gonna give it
the this ID from the homepage.
所以要使用它，我可以关闭这个文档页面，并且
So to use that,
I can close this docs page, and
我要做一个单文档页面请求。
I'm gonna do a single docs page request.
我想使用我们设置的这个页面 ID，现在我可以引用它了。
And I want to use this page ID that we
set up, so now I can reference this.
为了获取源代码，我需要确保我们请求的页面与该 ID 匹配。
And to source that I want to make sure
that the page we request matches that ID.
然后在里面，我想得到标题
And then inside of it
I wanna get the title
当它被更新的时候，我想让它相对于现在和
when it was updated, and
I want to make that relative to now and
然后我想要的身体，这就是我需要显示的页面。
then I want the body and
that's all I need to display the page.
所以我们要坚持这一点。
So we're gonna stick with that.
我想我忘记启动服务器了。
And I think I,
oops I forgot to start the server.
因此，让我们的纱线工作空间主题开发。
So let's yarn workspace theme-dev develop.
Jason Lengstorf: 好的，现在当我运行它的时候，它应该可以工作了。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Okay, and
now when I run it, it should work.
所以我们有了主页，一个小时前更新的，里面有这个身体。
So we've got the homepage, it was updated
an hour ago and it's got this body in it.
这样我就可以复制
So that I can then just copy and
直接降落在这里，修复我的缩进，使它看起来像我想要的方式。
drop straight in here, fix my indent so
that it looks the way I want.
所以这个页面 ID 必须设置好。
And so
this page ID is gonna have to get set.
但是我们可以使用上下文从 Gatsby 中的 Create Page API 设置它。
But we can set that from the Create
Page API in Gatsby using context.
当我们使用这个模板的时候，我们马上就会看到这一点。
We'll look at that in a second
when we go to use this, template.